Justin Cheng

New York, NY 10029 | https://github.com/jcheng01 | www.linkedin.com/in/chengjustin0222/

A third-year student pursuing a BS in Information Management & Technology with a focus in Front end development Classroom experience in high-demand programming languages along with experience in IT infrastructure.

EDUCATION

Syracuse University, iSchool for Information Studies – Syracuse, NY

September 2020 – May 2024

Major: Information Management & Technology

GPA: 3.68

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6, HTML, CSS/SCSS, JSON, Typescript Frameworks: React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Next.js, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, MySQL, Vite, ESlinting

Concepts: Scrum/Agile, REST APIs, Design patterns, MVC, Call stack event loop, Linked lists, Array functions, OOP, Object methods, Callbacks/Promises/Async Await, Prototypal Inheritance, Components, DOM manipulation, Mutability

FRONT END WEB APPLICATIONS

Replicated Hangman Game | React, Typescript, Vite, Tailwind CSS

February 2023 – February 2023

 Explored new building tools and deployed using GitHub pages. Practiced how to pass down states through different components in React with Typescript support

Image Recognition AI page | *React, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, API, JSON*

November 2022 – December 2022

 Created single web page using React and Tailwind to fetch JSON resources from two REST APIs. The goal is to demonstrate how an AI can understand a randomly generated image by parsing through outputted information

Pokémon Database | React, Tailwind CSS, API, JSON

September 2022 – October 2022

• Used Pokémon API to create an application using React.js and Tailwind imitating a database. The single page returns respective Pokémon data from API server using entered name to map through arrays of objects

My Webpage | HTML5, SCSS, ES6

August 2022 – December 2022

Personal Website created with raw HTML/SCSS/JavaScript. Implemented my own webpack to compile JS. Fun self-project to work on responsive UI - https://justincheng2.netlify.app/

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- **IST 363** Utilized PHP and custom theming with WordPress. At the end coordinate the application with React, WordPress, and Next.js to customize professional front-end imitation restaurant website
- **IST 466 (current)** Capstone course for Information Management and Technology majors. It is an integration of management strategies, information uses, and information technologies as related to professional conduct, ethics, and career strategies. In-depth review and use of case studies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Syracuse University - iSchool

Syracuse, NY

Student Technology Consultant

September 2022 – Present

- Collaborate with other IT department staff to resolve inquiries and ensure quality support at a rate of 100%
- Providing technical support over the phone, virtual ticketing, and in person, including configuration of student MS outlook, SU Blackboard, and AirOrangeX
- Trained in iSchool technology help desk resources, policies, and services to provide technical support over the phone and in person, and maintaining the smooth operation of the iSchool facilities

Syracuse University - Barnes Center

Syracuse, NY

Front Desk Receptionist

September 2020 – December 2021

- Provided excellent patron service, effectively maintaining a 99% satisfaction rate
- Answered Queries on wide-ranging service concerns utilizing facility virtual catalog